[
    {
        "question": "Which country has offered to sell its 5th generation fighter aircraft, F-35, to India?",
        "options": [
            "Israel  ",
            "Japan  ",
            "France  ",
            "United States "
        ],
        "answer": "United States "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country hosted the 4th Ministerial Conference on No Money for Terror?",
        "options": [
            "France  ",
            "Italy  ",
            "United States  ",
            "Germany  "
        ],
        "answer": "Germany  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company has signed an agreement with the Indian Oil Corporation Limited (IOCL) to supply 1.2 million tonnes per annum of liquified natural gas (LNG) for the next 10 years?",
        "options": [
            "Emirates National Oil Company (ENOC) ",
            "Abu Dhabi National Oil Company (ADNOC) ",
            "Exxon Mobil Corporation ",
            "Dubai Petroleum "
        ],
        "answer": "Abu Dhabi National Oil Company (ADNOC) "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary purpose of the RBI introducing Additional Factor of Authentication (AF",
        "options": [
            "for ",
            "To promote the use of international payment gateways ",
            "To enhance the security of cross-border transactions ",
            "To encourage cashless transactions within India ",
            "To eliminate transaction fees for international payments "
        ],
        "answer": "To promote the use of international payment gateways "
    },
    {
        "question": "How many non-banking financial companies, including Reliance Commercial Finance and IDFC Ltd, have returned their certificate of registration (COR) to the Reserve Bank of India?",
        "options": [
            "17 ",
            "15 ",
            "10 ",
            "20 "
        ],
        "answer": "20 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the U.S.-India COMPACT Initiative:  1. It will lay the foundation for deepening military partnerships.  2. Under this initiatives India and US aim to double bilateral trade to $500 billion by 2030 under “Mission 500.”  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary purpose of Matsya 6000, recently seen in the news?",
        "options": [
            "Space exploration ",
            "Deep-sea mining and biodiversity studies ",
            "Underwater military surveillance ",
            "Oil drilling "
        ],
        "answer": "Deep-sea mining and biodiversity studies "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company has partnered with UPM to modernize its IT infrastructure in the Nordic region?",
        "options": [
            "TCS ",
            "Wipro ",
            "Infosys ",
            "Cognizant "
        ],
        "answer": "TCS "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has approved the construction of a deepwater research facility in the South China Sea?",
        "options": [
            "India ",
            "United States ",
            "Japan ",
            "China "
        ],
        "answer": "China "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company partnered with Garuda Aerospace to develop advanced UAVs for defence, agriculture, and smart cities?",
        "options": [
            "Reliance Industries ",
            "Infosys ",
            "Tata Elxsi ",
            "Wipro "
        ],
        "answer": "Tata Elxsi "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company developed the world’s first DIVA marker vaccine for Lumpy Skin Disease (LSD)?",
        "options": [
            "? ",
            "Biovet ",
            "Serum Institute of India ",
            "Bharat Biotech ",
            "Cadila Healthcare "
        ],
        "answer": "? "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is hosting the first-ever International Conference on Governance in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "United States ",
            "India ",
            "United Kingdom ",
            "Japan "
        ],
        "answer": "India "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company signed an MoU with Saab to manufacture the Electronic Warfare Laser Warning System-310 (LWS-310) in India?",
        "options": [
            "Tata Defence ",
            "Bharat Dynamics Limited ",
            "Larsen & Toubro ",
            "Hindustan Aeronautice limited "
        ],
        "answer": "Hindustan Aeronautice limited "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company partnered with ONGC to collaborate on Battery Energy Storage Systems (BESS)?",
        "options": [
            "Tata Power ",
            "Adani Green Energy ",
            "NTPC ",
            "Reliance Power "
        ],
        "answer": "Tata Power "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is associated with the siblings who won the Global Best M-Gov Gold Award 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai ",
            "Hyderabad ",
            "Delhi ",
            "Bangalore "
        ],
        "answer": "Hyderabad "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state in India signed an MoU with the Swiss-Indian Chamber of Commerce for fostering international business collaboration?",
        "options": [
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Gujarat ",
            "Karnataka "
        ],
        "answer": "Karnataka "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company won the Forward Faster Sustainability Award 2025 in the Water Resilience category?",
        "options": [
            "Reliance Industries ",
            "NTPC ",
            "Tata Power ",
            "Adani Green "
        ],
        "answer": "NTPC "
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the NAMASTE Scheme:  1. It targets sewer and septic tank sanitation workers (SSWs) and wastepickers in urban areas of India.  2. It is jointly being implemented by the Ministry of Social Justice and Empowerment (MoSJE) and the Ministry of Housing and Urban Affairs.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct? ➢ NTPC Kanti has received the 11th edition of the FICCI Water Award 2023 under the “Industrial Water Use Efficiency” category. ➢ NTPC shines as the only Indian PSU to feature in Forbes “World’s Best Employers 2023” List. ➢ The central government has received about Rs 1,487 crore from NTPC as a dividend tranche. ➢ NTPC has been honoured with the prestigious Economic Times (ET) HR World Future Skills Awards 2023. ➢ NTPC climbs up 52 positions to 433rd rank in Forbes’ “The Global 2000” List. ➢ NTPC Kanti launches Girl Child Empowerment Mission (GeM)-2023. ➢ NTPC Group’s total installed capacity reaches 72,304 MW with first overseas capacity addition in Bangladesh. ➢ Country's largest power generation company NTPC Limited has been conferred with 'ATD Best Awards 2023' by Association for Talent Development (ATD), USA. ➢ NTPC and Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited (NPCIL) sign agreement for joint development of nuclear power plants. ➢ India’s largest power company NTPC Ltd has commissioned India’s first green hydrogen blending project at Kawas, Gujarat. ➢ About NTPC ➢ The NTPC which was earlier known as National Thermal Power Corporation of India is owned by the Government of India. It was set up in 1975. ➢ The Vindhyachal Thermal Power Station in the Singrauli district of Madhya Pradesh, with an installed capacity of 4,760MW, is currently the biggest thermal power plant in India. ➢ Headquarters: New Delhi ➢ Chairman and Managing Director: Gurdeep Singh  Follow us: Official Site, Telegram, Facebook, Instagram, Youtube 196",
        "options": [
            ", USA. ",
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "2 only "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ministry is organizing the Prime Minister's Yoga Awards 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Home Affairs ",
            "Ministry of External Affairs ",
            "Ministry of AYUSH ",
            "Ministry of Panchayati Raj "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of AYUSH "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the CEO of Standard Chartered Bank for India?",
        "options": [
            "Prabdev Singh ",
            "Zarin Daruwala ",
            "David Solomon ",
            "Jane Fraser "
        ],
        "answer": "Prabdev Singh "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has received RBI approval to open its first international branch at GIFT City IFSC in Gujarat?",
        "options": [
            "Bank of Maharashtra ",
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Punjab National Bank  ",
            "State Bank of India "
        ],
        "answer": "Bank of Maharashtra "
    },
    {
        "question": "Bima Vistaar portal, recently seen in the news, is launched by which organization?",
        "options": [
            "RBI ",
            "NPCI ",
            "IRDAI ",
            "SEBI "
        ],
        "answer": "IRDAI "
    },
    {
        "question": "Gravehawk System, recently seen in the news, is a short-range surface-to-air missile system developed by which one of the following countries?",
        "options": [
            "United States ",
            "Russia ",
            "France ",
            "United Kingdom "
        ],
        "answer": "United Kingdom "
    },
    {
        "question": "Exercise Komodo, recently in news, is a:",
        "options": [
            "multilateral army exercise ",
            "rescue exercise ",
            "bilateral air force exercise ",
            "multilateral naval exercise "
        ],
        "answer": "multilateral naval exercise "
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the TrailGuard AI system:  1. It is a camera-based alert system designed for enhancing wildlife conservation and promoting human-wildlife coexistence.  2. It autonomously detects target objects and transmits real-time alerts.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tectonic plates are involved in the location of Mount Etna, recently seen in the news?",
        "options": [
            "North American and South American Plates ",
            "African and Eurasian Plates ",
            "Pacific and Antarctic Plates ",
            "Indian and Australian Plates "
        ],
        "answer": "African and Eurasian Plates "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company partnered with Safran Electronics & Defense to manufacture the HAMMER weapon in India?",
        "options": [
            "Hindustan Aeronautics Limited ",
            "Tata Motors ",
            "Bharat Electronics Limited ",
            "Larsen & Toubro "
        ],
        "answer": "Bharat Electronics Limited "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution developed solar dehydration technology to help farmers preserve agricultural produce?",
        "options": [
            "IIT Bombay ",
            "IIT Kanpur ",
            "IIT Delhi ",
            "IIT Madras "
        ],
        "answer": "IIT Kanpur "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who inaugurated the 'Aadi Mahotsav 2025' in New Delhi?",
        "options": [
            "Droupadi Murmu ",
            "Narendra Modi ",
            "Rajnath Singh ",
            "Amit Shah "
        ],
        "answer": "Droupadi Murmu "
    },
    {
        "question": "For how many months has World No. 1 tennis player Jannik Sinner been suspended by WADA?",
        "options": [
            "2 months ",
            "3 months ",
            "4 months ",
            "6 months "
        ],
        "answer": "3 months "
    },
    {
        "question": "India is conducting the 6th edition of the joint military exercise 'Dharma Guardian' with which country?",
        "options": [
            "Vietnam ",
            "Russia ",
            "Singapore ",
            "Japan "
        ],
        "answer": "Japan "
    },
    {
        "question": "How much prize money has been announced for the winner of the ICC Champions Trophy 2025?",
        "options": [
            "2.14 million  ",
            "2.24 million  ",
            "2.34 million  ",
            "2.44 million "
        ],
        "answer": "2.24 million  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the author of the book titled \"Akashvani: A Century of Stories from All India Radio\"?",
        "options": [
            "Karan Johar with Poonam Saxena ",
            "Ram Gopal Varma and Ruskin Bond ",
            "Kanji Ishiwara and Rana Chhina ",
            "Vikrant Pande and Neelesh Kulkarni "
        ],
        "answer": "Vikrant Pande and Neelesh Kulkarni "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the author of the book titled \"I AM A SOLDIER'S WIFE : The Life and Love of Toni Lidder\"?",
        "options": [
            "Geetika Lidder ",
            "Prashant Bhushan ",
            "Ram Gopal Varma ",
            "Poonam Saxena "
        ],
        "answer": "Geetika Lidder "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is excluded from the eligible projects for Sovereign Green Bonds (SGrBs) in India?",
        "options": [
            "Solar energy projects ",
            "Wind energy projects ",
            "Nuclear power generation ",
            "Urban mass transportation projects "
        ],
        "answer": "Nuclear power generation "
    },
    {
        "question": "Javelin Anti-Tank Guided Missile, recently seen in the news, is developed by which country?",
        "options": [
            "North Korea ",
            "Russia ",
            "United States ",
            "India "
        ],
        "answer": "United States "
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the NAKSHA Programme:  1. It aims to create and update land records in urban areas to ensure accurate and reliable documentation of land ownership.  2. It will empower citizens and improve ease of living in urban areas.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 "
    }
]